http://www.roho.co.uk/privacy-cookies

PRIVACY STATEMENT, GDPR, & COOKIES
Robin Hood Watersports has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web-site.
Your personal data is important. So important that there are a range of laws in place to safeguard it (the most important of which is the General Data Protection Regulation or “GDPR”). Robin Hood Watersports are committed to doing its part to protect your personal data and comply with those laws.
In practice, this means that all personal data which we hold about you will be:
Used lawfully, fairly and in a transparent way
Collected only for valid purploses that we have clearly explained to you and not used in any way that is incompatible with those purposes
Relevant to the purposes we have told you about and limited only to those purposes
Accurate and kept up to date
Kept only as long as necessary for the purposes we have told you about
Kept securely
Personal Data Processing
MetadataYou may use the Website without providing any personal data about you. In this case, we will collect only the following metadata that result from your usage of the Website: browser type and version, operating system and interface, website from which you are visiting us (referrer URL), webpage(s) you are visiting on our Website, date and time of accessing our Website, and internet protocol (IP) address.
Your IP address will be used to enable your access to our Website. Once the IP address is no longer necessary for this purpose, we will shorten your IP address by removing the last octet of your IP address. The metadata, including the shortened IP address, will be used to improve the quality and services of our Website and services by analysing the usage behaviour of our users.
AccountIf you create an account on our Website you will be asked to provide the following personal data about you: name, gender (salutation), date of birth, postal address, email address, telephone number, selected password for your account, payment details, invoicing and delivery address and your preferences in receiving marketing from us (voluntary). We process such personal data for purposes of account administration, answering your queries or information requests, providing desired products or services, providing you with marketing materials where you have provided consent for us to do so, to the extent permitted by applicable law, analysing your interests for marketing purposes, improving our Website according to usage patterns, and for technical administration or other purposes to which you have agreed.
Product OrdersIf you order a product via our Website we collect and process the following personal data about you: name, gender (salutation), postal address, email address, telephone number, payment details, invoicing and delivery address, type and amount of product, purchase price, order date, order status, product returns, customer care requests, and your preferences in receiving marketing from us (voluntary). We process such personal data for purposes of carrying out the contractual relationship and the product order, providing customer care services, compliance with legal obligations, defending, establishing and exercising legal claims, providing you with marketing materials where you have provided consent for us to do so, to the extent permitted by applicable law, and analysing your interests for marketing purposes.
CompetitionsIf you participate in a competition, we collect and process the following personal data about you: name, gender (salutation), postal address, email address, telephone number and selection as winner. We process such personal data for purposes of carrying out the competition, informing the winner, delivering the prize to the winner, carrying out the event, and providing you with marketing materials where you have provided us consent to do so, to the extent permitted by applicable law, and analysing your interests for marketing purposes.
NewsletterIf you request to receive our newsletter, we collect and process the following personal data about you: name, address, date of birth, gender and email address, and your preferences in receiving marketing from us via emails, SMS or postal mails (voluntary). We process such personal data for purposes of providing the newsletter and other marketing materials to the extent permitted by applicable law and where you have provided us consent to do so, and analysing your interests for marketing purposes.
Spam
We do not use and do not support the use of spam. If you receive any unsolicited bulk email mentioning Robin Hood Watersports, please report it to us at accounts@roho.co.uk. We shall investigate and deal with your complaint promptly. We have a zero tolerance approach towards spam.
Personal Information
Some of the services at our site require you to give us your personal information like your name, email address and the URL of your web site. Your personal information is only used to contact you for the information or services requested by you. Your personal information is never used to contact you for any other purpose. We shall never disclose your personal information to any third party. We have taken the necessary security measures to ensure that your personal information remains confidential and that no third party can obtain unauthorized access to your personal information.
CookiesA cookie is a piece of text that is stored on your computer by your web browser. We use cookies to monitor how people use our site. This helps us to understand how our customers and potential customers use our website so we can develop and improve the design, layout and function of the site.
More detailed information on cookies can be found at www.allaboutcookies.org.
How RoHo uses cookiesRoHo and our third party partners may set the following types of cookies when you visit www.roho.co.uk (the "Website"):
Session cookiesWithout these our website won't work properly.
Session cookies are used to remember what is in your shopping basket and what stage you are at in the checkout process. Session cookies expire and are deleted automatically after you close your browser or end your session.
Accepting these cookies is a condition of using the websites. You can chose to restrict these cookies if you wish, however the site will not function correctly.
Function and Analytics CookiesThese cookies help improve your visit experience
These cookies help us improve the site by measuring any errors and analyse how visitors choose to use the site. These cookies share information with our partners to provide a service on our website and expire by default after 30 days.
These cookies cannot be used to identify who you are and will not be used to target you with adverts on other websites.
You can choose to restrict these cookies; however it may reduce the functionality and your experience of the site.
Google Analytics: We track web site usage using Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets a cookie in order to evaluate your use of the website and compile reports for us on activity on the website.
Google stores the information collected by the cookie on servers in the United States. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using the website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.
How to reject or delete this cookiehttp://www.google.com/intl/en/privacypolicy.html
YouTube and other media providers: To support our website, we sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube and Flickr. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Flickr, you may be presented with cookies from these websites. The cookies accompanying any ads allow them and their advertisers to monitor the effectiveness of the ads (e.g. by using statistical analysis cookies). RoHo does not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.
Social Media and Tracking CookiesThese cookies are for social media and advertising
These cookies are generally associated with 'Like', 'Share' or 'Add' buttons from third party social media providers. In return for 'sharing' with your social network, the service provider remembers your visit to our site and uses this to build a profile of your interests.
The information collected by these cookies may then be used by the third party provider to serve you with tailored advertising on other websites.
Our advertisers may also set cookies on your hard drive to track the performance of the advertisements or banners placed on our website. These cookies also enable us to tailor our online advertising. The cookies accompanying any ads allow us and our advertisers to monitor the effectiveness of the ads (e.g. by using statistical analysis cookies).
You can choose to restrict these cookies; however this may prevent us from providing you with some services.
Disabling cookiesIf you do not want us to use cookies in your browser, you can remove cookies from your computer's hard drive, or set your browser to block cookies or to send a warning notice before a cookie is stored on your computer. However, please note that you may not be able to use some of the services on our website or other websites without cookies.
You can find information on disabling cookies at www.allaboutcookies.org.
New lawWe are aware of the EU Directive 2009/136/EC which came into force in the UK on 26th May 2011. We are always reviewing our privacy policies and website practices and considering how best to implement the changes that are required to the way that we use cookies on the Website as a result of this new law.
Contacting Us
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the privacy practices of this site, our use of cookies, or your dealings with this web site, please contactAccounts@roho.co.uk
Changes to this Privacy Policy
We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, regulatory or operational requirements. We will notify you of any such changes, including when they will take effect, by updating the "Last revised" date below or as otherwise required by applicable law. Your continued use of our Website after any such updates take effect will constitute acceptance of those changes. If you do not accept updates to this Privacy Policy, you should stop using our Website.
Last revised - May 24th 2018
